<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jennifer Esquivel]]></title>
  <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-25T12:40:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jennifer Esquivel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tenth Week Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/21/tenth-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-21T20:50:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/21/tenth-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Only one week left?  It&rsquo;s hard to believe.  Although it was sometimes very difficult, I have learned more than I ever expected from YWeb Academy.  Among many other things, this week we have been working on our group projects.  My group is creating an interactive website to help Spanish speakers learn HTML tags by providing English and Spanish translations as well as mnemonics, contextual and images to aid in memorization.  We intend for our app to allow users to contribute by adding additional definitions and information in the future.  This week on Thursday, I participated in the Ruby on Rails workshop and built a small app (on Heroku).  That night I went to Hype Harvest for YWeb Academy and finally I attended the Madison + Ruby Conference, which was great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Nine: Zendesk Visit]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/08/ninth-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-08T20:51:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/08/ninth-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow, time does fly and we&rsquo;re having fun at Our YWeb Academy web dev bootcamp program is moving fast.  Week eight is already over.  How did that happen?  This week concluded with a site visit to <em>zendesk</em> on the square, in downtown Madison.  I was immediately impressed with the place and people.  First impression was that this is a wonderful work environment.  The business is located in the glass building downtown and the office design is lovely.  The workstations and office are simple, yet elegant (work stations are adjustable in height for sitting or standing at desks).  There a beautiful living moss wall at the entry desk.  It has 360 views of the Capitol, the lakes and Isthmus.  The light that floods the space makes for a wonderful, indeed-zen-like, working environment. The office design is condusive to happy worktime.</p>

<p>Beyond the visual space, the energy and vibe was great.  People who work there smile and genuinely give off good energy.  Everyone proclaims to love their job&ndash;and I believe them!  Lillana began our visit with some youtube videos about the company.  Those added to my sense that this place would be a good fit for me, if I worked there.</p>

<p>We took a tour of the offices.  I got a sense that the working environment fostered creativity and professional development.  The work environment seems casual, upbeat and energetic.  I was thrilled to learn about how zendesk gives back to the community&ndash;both financially and in volunteer hours.  Impressive.   One of the most important factors in where I work and what I do is feeling that my work makes the world a better place and helps people.  I certainly got that sense from zendesk.  Overall, I really enjoyed meeting the people there and learning about the work.  It seemed like a very fullfilling and exciting place to work where the people are appreciated and really believe in the work and product they produce.</p>

<p>There seems to be a tremendous diversity of work opportunities at <em>zendesk.</em>  A few employees gave us short presentations about their backgrounds and their work at zendesk.  People with all kinds of backgrounds work there.  The people are interesting and diverse. They all seemed to be happy to be there.  I didn&rsquo;t get a sense that anyone dreaded going to work&ndash;as I have noticed in other employment situations. A think that is part of the reason the business is so successful&ndash;great people who enjoy being there and doing what they do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Seven: Teach the Class Something]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/27/seventh-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-27T20:50:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/27/seventh-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to do (one of) my &ldquo;teach the class something&rdquo; projects on illustrating ideas and taking sketchnotes:  &ldquo;You Can Draw.&rdquo;&ldquo;    Often I hear people say, "I can&rsquo;t draw&rdquo; or &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not an artist.&rdquo;  First, I want people to realize that they CAN learn to draw and feel confident about expressing themselves artistically.  Anyone can draw.  If people know techniques and practice, almost anyone can learn to draw realistically.  But drawing doesn&rsquo;t need to be fine art.  What I would like to teach the class is how to literally illustrate ideas and why it is important.</p>

<p>75% of our information intake is visual (citation: some online video).  I don&rsquo;t know what that means, exactly.  What about blind people?  Touch?  Smell?  I need to check that statistic.  As you may know, 58.7% of statistics are made up on the spot.  (That&rsquo;s what I thought sounded like a very specific percentage, anyway.)  The point is that sketching is very useful:  in meetings, for brainstorming, when talking with clients about projects, to explain something that is hard to put into words.  A picture is worth 1000 words, so why not sketch out some of our thoughts and ideas?  Additionally, drawing and reading sketchnotes uses different parts of the brain.  Learning to &ldquo;Think Visually&rdquo; can open up creative energy, make connections, and come up with new or innovative ideas that you wouldn&rsquo;t have otherwise thought of&hellip;</p>

<p>I will continue this after I have completed my presentation(s).  I am going to do a few of them for extra credit, since I researched a few ideas anyway.  Another one is a few big points about databases what to always do (be consistent, timely and accurate and several other things with funny or awkward examples) and what not to do (e.g., leave your customer database on a computer connected to the internet, <em>with no security or backup</em> (NO firewall, or antivirus, no other version of the data except on one computer&rsquo;s harddrive)&ndash;like I discovered (and immediately fixed) at one small business that I was hired to manage.</p>

<p>FIX THIS BLOG>&hellip; typed it fast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Six]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/25/sixth-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-25T20:50:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/25/sixth-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, among many other things, we are creating html skeletons.  First we did mock navigation, then thumbnails, and finally wireframes.  I found those fun to do&ndash;<em>ACTUALLY Fun</em>&ndash;since I really enjoy being creative.  Now, from the wireframes, we are doing bare bones (errors are fine at this moment) .html coding for our pages. I am pasting my index.html code (that I am currently working on) into this blog.  (I know it is a mess, but I will have plenty of time to check and make sure there are no errors.  Also, I&rsquo;d like to come back and see where I was at this point (&frac12; way through).  I added a few meta tags that don&rsquo;t work yet, but I think I&rsquo;d like to include them in my website.</p>

<p>This is my index page.  It is certainly not great, but it is simply a start.  Once I get the coding corrected and add the css, I think I will be beautiful&hellip;(at least to me.)</p>

<pre><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Jennifer Esquivel's Website&lt;/title&gt;
      &lt;meta charset="UTF-8"&gt;
</code></pre>

<p><em>[This (below) is some code that I got from various sources outside of class.  I have it here to remind me to figure out if I want to insert it into my index page, or any page.  I have about 20 pages of detailed notes that I wrote from youtube videos and online sources&ndash;from outside of class.  It is probably good to know, regardless.  Maybe we will go over this sometime soon in class, anyway.]</em></p>

<pre><code>      &lt;meta name="description" content="Description of the site."/&gt;

      &lt;meta name="keywords" content="Web, Jennifer Esquivel, resume, YWCA, Madison, graphic art, CSS, html, JavaScript, web design, web development, portfolio"/&gt;

      &lt;meta name="robots" content="index, follow"/&gt;

      &lt;link rel="icon" href="nameoficon.ico"/&gt;

      &lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="style.css"

      &lt;script src="NameJavaScriptfile.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;/head&gt;
      &lt;body&gt;    
        &lt;div id="wrapper"&gt;
        &lt;header&gt;
          &lt;a href="desktop image location"&gt;
            &lt;img id="websitelogo" alt="Logo" src="http://localhost/file/name.gif"/&gt; 
          &lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;h1&gt;Jennifer Esquivel's Portfolio&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;/header&gt;
        &lt;div class="search")/&gt;
          &lt;form&gt;
        &lt;input type="search" placeholder="Search here..."&gt;&lt;/input&gt;"
          &lt;/form&gt;
            &lt;nav id="horzNav"&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;
                &lt;a href="Portfolio.html"&gt;Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;a href="Resume.html"&gt;Resume&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;a href="Contact.html"&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/nav&gt;
        &lt;main id="content"&gt;

        &lt;section&gt;
          &lt;article&gt;
              &lt;h2&gt;Another heading&lt;/h2&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;In this section I write a bunch of stuff. &lt;br&gt; Note to self: The &amp;lt; br &amp;gt; tag is after the word stuff. To get it to show, I use the charcter elements.&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;aside&gt;Practice skeleton -aside
          &lt;/aside&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;

          &lt;h2&gt;Other tags I might want to use&lt;/h2&gt;

          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bold&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;ol id="ordered list nested indented"&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;One&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Two&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Italic&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emphasis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Strike&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;

        &lt;/section&gt;
        &lt;section&gt;
           &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Another section: Bold text to see what it looks like&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/section&gt;

        &lt;h2&gt;Things I need to figure out how to get into my head&lt;/h2&gt;

        &lt;aside&gt; This is stuff below (now inserted into &lt;del&gt;into another file&lt;/del&gt; head) I want to include in my final website, but when I put it into my header, it shows up like the utf-8 does.
        &lt;/aside&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/main&gt;
    &lt;footer&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&amp;copy; 2015 &lt;a href="mailto:jeneesquivel@gmail.com"&gt;Send me an email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/footer&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Eight: Time Is Flying and Class Is *actually* Fun!]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/25/eighth-week-blog/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-25T20:50:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/25/eighth-week-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am writing this week&rsquo;s blog at the beginning of the week (Sunday morning, actually).  This will be one more thing to check off the &lsquo;to do&rsquo; list and free up my time for other projects.  I want to make sure that I have a blog submitted early so that I can devote my attention this week to my porfolio website and learning more JQuery, for example.  ]</p>

<p>I am really loving creating things (pages from scratch) with html and css.  It is exciting to see how pages&ndash;almost magically&ndash; render, sometimes even with just tiny changes in the source code.  I feel a little like a kid, wide-eyed and in awe of something and surprised myself with something I made.  Yep, I did that all by myself.  I did so much code experimentation (adding every possible fancy code idea, trick and thing I came across) that I finally decided on the design and feel of my page (the opposite of all the flashy things I played around with.) I started over.  Clear.  Simple.  To the point.  The process of getting there was fun, though.  I still have lots to polish and bugFixing to do.  I need things to be more clear in my mind, but I have no doubt that I will get there.  Plus, I now know that I will enjoy learning, doing and getting there.  Now that things are all starting to come together more, I enjoy this course more each day.</p>

<p>This leads me to believe that I will be quite happy working in this.  Working with computers, creative work, and design combined with web development is all fun for me.  (The infamous) &ldquo;they&rdquo; say that people should choose a career in something they love and they will never &lsquo;work&rsquo; a day.  Makes sense.  When I taught a class in wildlife ecology at UW-Madison, I loved it.  It was like I couldn&rsquo;t get enough.  I had fun teaching and learned as much from my students (insights, questions, etc) as I taught them.  I feel like when I start and internship, and after, I will feel the same as I did about teaching.  I am excited to see.  It seems like a good idea to get paid as my career to do something I enjoy doing anyway.  (I think my next blog will be about the many reasons why working in this field is such a great match for me.)  We are going to &ldquo;create something cool&rdquo; using JQuery and this <em>cool JQuery thing</em> is due by this Wednesday. JQuery is very new to us, so this should be interesting.  However, <em>all</em> of these computer languages were new to me as we learned them, so I expect this will be similar to those.  I&rsquo;ll go with the flow and make it happen (although what I will make happen is not yet clear to me).  If I have time, I may revisit this blog to add an addendum about the JQuery project, after it is complete.  I&rsquo;m intrigued anyway.</p>

<p>I find that while I am doing assignments and work on topics (JavaScript, CSS, etc.), I tend to actually &ldquo;get it&rdquo; and understand it better about a week after we finish.  Although I did the worksheets, I understood Chapter 02 of the Eloquent JavaScript textbook much better <em>after</em> we completed <em>Chapter 03.</em>  Chapter 04 will make more sense when I complete Chapter 05, and so on. So, while I am working on something, I don&rsquo;t fully understand it.  I remember being totally confused by some things about command line that now seem second nature because I use them every day.  I remind myself that practice makes this much more clear and that I often learn this type of material best by doing. After using the new info in various contexts, I grasp it more.  I finally &lsquo;git&rsquo; more of the git commands now. &lt;&ndash;I also dig cheesy puns&ndash;after I buried them because they were so bad. I find it fun and gouda to play with words&ndash;especially now, since I have insomnia.  Sometimes I am easily amused by punny nonsense.  Should I go continue?  No.  Like most of this semester, I should get some much-needed sleep.)</p>

<p>Since I have logged over 100 hours outside the class.  I logged these hours to keep perfect attendence, despite needing to miss classes due to my child having surgery and to learn more about subjects that interested me.  Since we only had a very brief survey of a few topics that piqued my interest, I learned more about those independently.  For example, I believe I spent about 30 hours outside of class just diving deeper into design principles, web design, best practices, color theory and other topics that I felt were important and interesting to me.  I enjoy learning, so I am sure I will continue learning more about these and more.  I also learned that I will still have access to some of the online programs, school and readings even after the class ends.  That is exciting to me as I would like to independently learn some other computer languages and expand on (or review) what I have already learned.  This summer <em>bootcamp</em> semester is extremely intense.  We cover a tremendous amount of material in a short time.  Although I am generally doing well in the class, I intend to review all material once I have a chance.  I want to clarify, in my mind, several things that were not completely clear (e.g., with JavaScript).  I would also like to learn more advanced JavaScript CSS, Ruby and Python, just to mention a few.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Five]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/17/fifth-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-17T20:50:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/17/fifth-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the fifth week ends, we are approaching the halfway point in class.  This program is challenging and we are learning lots of material, at a rapid pace.  However the format of the class makes it so that each week material from past weeks becomes clearer as we build upon what we have learned.  I am doing lots of work outside of class and learning additional information beyond what we are learning in class.  I have several dozen hours learning about the elements of design, design principles, and color theory, for example.  I intend to continue education outside of class to learn more about topics that interest me or topics I need to review to know them well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Four: The Code of My Dreams]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/10/fourth-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-10T20:49:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/10/fourth-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my fourth week&rsquo;s blog entry.  At this point, I have started to dream about code sometimes.  I find myself solving JavaScript problems as they appear in my dreams.  I remember when I first learned Spanish, I knew I was fairly fluent when I started dreaming <em>in</em> Spanish.  However, if I start dreaming <em>in</em> command-line, CSS or JavaScript, I guess I will have to redefine (literally and figuratively) my understanding of reprograming my mind.</p>

<p>In this week&rsquo;s mock-Scrum workshop, I learned a ton.  My group developed a desktop application from concept to release.  Ours was a to do list for completing office tasks, with extra features and incentives.  The concept was for existing employees at a business to have incentives to do miscellaneous office tasks so that the owner of the business wouldn&rsquo;t need to hire another salaried employee as an office manager to do the tasks.  To distinguish our app from existing ones, we decided that tasks would have a point value assigned to them and that those points would be redeemed for some incentive (decided upon by the management/administration.)</p>

<p>Our team decided to allow the app administrator to create &lsquo;to do&rsquo; tasks and assign a point value to them.  Like a Trello board, the task cards get moved from a to do column to a &ldquo;done&rdquo; column as an employee chooses them and claims the points for completing each.  Tasks refresh at set intervals, if needed (daily tasks reset daily, e.g.)  The employee can then claim the points earned for rewards made available by the owner (examples might be a massage gift certificate, extra vacation time, or a flight to somewhere.)  We decided to integrate it with <strong>SLack</strong> so that employees could comment about the task, if needed.  I came up with the branding and logo concept. I thought &ldquo;DoPoint&rdquo; was a cute play on words.  The &ldquo;t&rdquo; in the word would be a themometer.  The themometer-like graphic repeats through the app to measure each employee&rsquo;s progress.  There were many other features and things we learned while doing the project.  We all played different roles (job titles) so that we could get a better understanding of how a real world team works on a project.  Overall, I learned a tremendous amount and had fun doing it.</p>

<p>We also started on basic design.  Although I have studied graphic design and fine arts, and am an artist, I learned several new things.  I refreshed my memory about color theory and other design concepts.  Overall, it was a great week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Again: Week Three]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/02/third-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-02T20:49:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/07/02/third-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The second week of YWeb Academy was fun.  <em>Actually fun.</em>  Now, I am getting more familiar with the material, so it is going more smoothly.  This week we covered lots of material and I felt a sense of accomplishment when the week was through.  I studied lots at home and worked on extra work.  I am trying to get a rounded sense of all that is web development so that when I work somewhere, I have an idea of what is a good match for me, my skills and interests.  I learn quickly, so gaining new skills shouldn&rsquo;t be an issue.</p>

<p>I got my Master&rsquo;s degree from UW-Madison while having a new baby, working a state job and being a teaching assitant for an upper level class.  I attended seminars until I gave birth and was back in seminar two days after.I am not sure how I did all of that; but having done it, I know I can accomplish anything.  YWeb is intense, but I have good time management skills and dedication.  I am sure I will do great in YWeb as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/24/second-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-24T20:49:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/24/second-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The second week of YWeb Academy was fun.  Now, I am getting more familiar with the material, so it is going more smoothly.  This week we covered lots of material and I felt a sense of accomplishment when the week was through.  I studied lots at home and worked on extra work.  I am trying to get a rounded sense of all that is web development so that when I work somewhere, I have an idea of what is a good match for me, my skills and interests.  I learn quickly, so gaining new skills shouldn&rsquo;t be an issue.  I got a Master&rsquo;s degree from UW-Madison while being pregnant, having a new baby working a state job and being a teaching assitant for an upper level class.  I am not sure how I did all of that; but having done it, I know I can accomplish anything.  YWeb is intense, but I have good time management skills and dedication.  I am sure I will do great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to My Blog.]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/21/first-week-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-21T20:48:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeneesquivel.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/21/first-week-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first blog entry.  I am Jennifer E Esquivel&ndash;a student at the YWeb Academy and this is the last day of week one.  I can&rsquo;t believe how much we have learned in such a short time.  This is intense.  I will add to my blog weekly. This first one is short.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
